New team. New attitude. New mission.
The Expendables 3 is a action, adventure, thriller
film directed by Patrick Hughes.
Barney, Christmas and the rest of the team comes face-to-face with Conrad
Stonebanks, who years ago co-founded The Expendables with Barney.
Stonebanks subsequently became a ruthless arms trader and someone
who Barney was forced to kill… or so he thought.
Stonebanks, who eluded death once before, now is making it his mission
to end The Expendables -- but Barney has other plans.
Barney decides that he has to fight old blood with new blood, and brings in a new era of Expendables
team members, recruiting individuals who are younger, faster and more tech-savvy.
The latest mission becomes a clash of classic old-school style versus
high-tech expertise in the Expendables’ most personal battle yet.
Barney Ross, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Lee Christmas, played by Jason Statham.
Max Drummer, played by Harrison Ford.
Trench, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Conrad Stonebanks, played by Mel Gibson.
Doc, played by Wesley Snipes.
The Expendables 3 is a 2014 American action thriller film directed by Patrick Hughes and
written by Creighton Rothenberger, Katrin Benedikt and Sylvester Stallone.
It is the third installment in The Expendables franchise and the sequel
to The Expendables (2010) and The Expendables 2 (2012).
The film features an ensemble cast of largely action film actors consisting of Stallone, Jason Statham, Antonio Banderas, Jet Li, Wesley Snipes, Dolph Lundgren,
Kelsey Grammer, Randy Couture, Terry Crews, Kellan Lutz, Ronda Rousey, Glen Powell, Victor Ortiz, Mel Gibson, Harrison Ford, and Arnold Schwarzenegger.
The story follows the mercenary group known as The Expendables as they come into conflict with ruthless arms
dealer Conrad Stonebanks, the Expendables' co-founder, who is determined to destroy the team.
The film premiered in London on August 4, 2014 and was released
theatrically on August 15, 2014, by Lionsgate.
Unlike the first two films in the franchise, The Expendables 3 received a PG-13
rating instead of an R rating, which upset many fans of the franchise.
Partly due to negative critical reviews and being leaked three weeks before its scheduled release, the film grossed $214.7 million worldwide on an estimated
$90–100 million budget, becoming the lowest-grossing film of the franchise until the sequel, Expend4bles, was released on September 22, 2023.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
mercenary, rescue mission, arms dealer, sequel.
The tone is intense.